Hey...
Rin.
Wake up.
Come over here.
It was just a dream.
There's nothing to worry about.
Huh?
I dunno about tomorrow.
It's different than a sacrifice. Something's off.
I don't think it's like some penalty game.
So, why? I don't get it at all.
I'm a little bit unsatisfied, but your presence
right now is more than just important.
There's no such thing in this world
as something never-ending.
Crying isn't painful, it's love's sweet drops, sweet drops!
I want to keep dreaming forever, ya know?
I want to be more kind, ya know?
As long as I’m with you, I’m happy.
Girls sure are strong, ya know?
But sometimes we're weak, ya know?
Our wish is to be happy, happy, happy!
And those days will be happy, too!
Just wanna make you happy!
Here, I'll take one, too.
Grandpa used to make them, too!
Is that right?
You know what, I want my own knife.
You're still a little too young...
They've got 'em for kids, too!
Seriously?
I'll think about it.
Come on, let's eat.
We've gotta get going soon.
Okay.
Isn't the baby cute?
Yeah.
I am Kawachi, a relative
of Kaga Rin-san's father.
Right now, Rin-san and I...
Rin and I are living together.
Oh...
Um... You are Yoshii Masako-san...
You are Rin's mother, correct?
Um...
M-Me?
Yes...
I'd like to meet you in person
and talk about something.
Near you is fine, so if
you could pick a place...
Place... Um...
Oh, I don't know... I guess in
the shopping area, at the...
Sorry, I don't have any
idea where you live...
This is so cute!
More crafts, Mom?
You made this flower, too?
That's right. It's called embroidery.
Wow! That's amazing!
When you get a little bigger,
I'll teach you how to do it.
Really?
Since you're so good with
your hands, Rin-chan.
So what's your plan?
I can't say until I meet her...
Well, keep an eye on Rin while I'm out.
Daikichi...
It's important.
So have a good long talk with her.
Mom's been looking forward to
spending time with Rin-chan anyway.
This is really close to Grandpa's house...
Welcome!
Are you alone, sir?
One more person is coming afterwards.
Non-smoking, please...
Watch out! You're gonna spill!
The stress just keeps building...
Believe me, I've been there!
Americano, please.
One Americano!
Would you like anything else?
No, thank you.
This is very nice, Saionji-sensei!
But I'd expect no less from you.
Now you just need to give
each character some trauma,
two or three problems each...
D-Don't you think that's overdoing it?
No, I think that'd be perfect!
It doesn't make sense...
After she went to all the trouble
of erasing her every trace
in Grandpa's house...
Does she still live near here?
Then I'll see you soon, Sensei.
Thank you for coming.
Pretty slipshod for someone who ran off...
Mama, I have to pee!
Yeah, yeah. Just hold it a few minutes.
Hello? Where are you now?
I'm already in the restaurant.
S-Souichi-san...
Wrong. I'm his grandson.
She's like a little kid...
U-Um... I'm sorry about that.
It's just that you look so much like him...
That's okay...
In fact, just recently,
someone else told me that...
But now that I have a chance
to really see you...
Souichi-san had a kinder look about him...
Yeah...
I brought a photo of Rin.
Thank you...
It was taken at the beginning of the year.
At a rice cake-pounding
party at her nursery school.
She seems...
so much like a young lady...
Before, someone called you "Sensei"...
W-Were you watching?
But the name is...
That's my pen name.
Sorry...
I'm totally out of it after pulling an
all-nighter because of deadline hell...
Hah...?
Is that work the reason you left Rin behind?
Um...
And apparently you made Rin think
that you were just the housekeeper,
but is that from when she was born?
Mm... My work is the reason.
But it's also true that
I was Souichi-san's maid.
Even while I was pregnant, though,
I was resolved not to think
of Rin as my daughter.
S-Sorry. I'm not sure I understand...
For the longest time, I
wasn't popular at all...
Then, just as I was about to
finally land a major assignment,
I found out I was pregnant...
And it's not the kind of work you can
do and raise a kid at the same time...
But Souichi-san encouraged me to
have the child nevertheless...
Every day, I'd either work or stay in
bed, and just got fatter and flabbier...
But even so, weirdly enough...
When Rin was born, I thought she was
so cute, my heart went out to her.
Weirdly enough...?
That's why, even while telling
myself that Rin wasn't my daughter,
I tried desperately to
both work and raise her.
But it was tough trying to be a day person...
And sometimes I have to go
out at night for meetings,
which means being up late...
It was just physically impossible...
Um... I hear that Rin stayed with
you in an apartment at night?
Yes...
Did you ever go out at night then?
Well, it was more the middle of the night.
Rin was already sleeping, so I
went out for a little while...
And sometimes Souichi-san watched her then...
Even now, Rin occasionally
wakes up after midnight.
Didn't you ever think about
how she'd feel when she did,
and no one was next to her?
But... Then how else was I supposed
to raise a child on my own?
Well, my grandfather wanted the three
of you to be a family, didn't he?
Do you have a problem with me
continuing to live with Rin?
No.
I'm not Rin's mother anymore,
so I don't have the right to
make those kinds of choices.
Even though it's beyond dispute
that Rin was in your belly?
Th-That has nothing to do with it!
How do you actually feel about Rin?
Is she important to you or not?
I-I don't know...
Um... I just have one favor to ask...
What is it?
When that girl goes to school, please
let her use your family name.
Hah? My family name?
If her surname is different
from that of her guardian,
I'm sure she'll have a rough time...
Would you just promise me that?
I know where you're coming from, but...
But I can't promise that...
She's always been Kaga Rin up to now...
I don't think a person's name is
such a simple thing to change...
I'm a woman,
so I don't have any great affection
for or attachment to my family name.
One day, it might change anyways...
Rin's a woman, too, so she
probably feels the same way.
Yeah, but Rin's still six...
And that's not what I'm talking about.
Besides which, it's just
your own personal opinion!
There's only one thing that's important!
And that's her name, "Rin",
which Souichi-san gave her.
Now, excuse me!
Look...
I'm a man, so I don't really
get what you're saying.
But...
I can talk to her about it.
Talk to her about it?
You'd make that little girl decide?!
Don't you think that's cruel?!
I...
I'm thinking about what's best for Rin.
And making the decision for
her is what would be cruel.
First, I've got to ask Rin how she feels.
After that, the two of
us will decide together,
and I'll let you know afterwards
what the answer is.
It sounds like she's no good!
I'm sure of it!
Who would abandon a cute
little girl like that?!
It defies common sense!
Well, she does at least worry about Rin...
It's just, she's a little odd.
It's like she has no awareness of getting
other people involved in her mess.
What are you talking about?!
Naturally, a mother would
worry about her daughter!
But if she really worried about
her, she'd want to see her!
Now, now. We don't know the woman's
circumstances. Have an orange.
What did Grandpa ever see in her?
Well, at this stage, that hardly matters...
The thing is, she demanded that when
Rin starts school, she use my surname.
Oh, well, I agree with that.
Of course a child should have the
same family name as her guardian.
Well, yeah... I understand, but...
How am I supposed to explain that to Rin?
When she's already got a name of her own...
Well, she's a girl,
so her family name will change
anyway when she gets married...
That again?!
What again?
It's much more preferable for her
to use our family name at school
than let someone make a crack about her
differing name and hurt her feelings.
And you think she can keep that all straight?
There's a lot going on,
even in elementary school.
I just don't want things
to be difficult for her.
Fine, I'll adopt Rin.
Wha...?!
As long as she doesn't object...
That way, she'll really be Kawachi Rin...
Yeah, that way's more natural...
Don't talk so glibly about
such an important thing!
I'm not being glib!
This is something that's gotta
be decided, am I right?!
It's all the same if it's now or later!
Easy, easy...
It's not all the same!
Yes, it is! It absolutely is!
I'm not passing the baton to anyone else.
That would be the worst
thing I could do to Rin.
If it's for Rin, I can accept my fate.
Kid's Knife
Here.
This is mine?
Yep, it's yours.
But you can only use when
I'm next to you, got it?
If you promise me that,
you get to use the knife.
I promise!
You know what, I'll make curry for you!
You serious?
Tonight!
Let's make it tomorrow...
Huh?
I forget, do I push or pull?
Give it here a sec...
Oh, like this...
Daikichi, you're good at that!
Yeah, well, I lived alone for a long time...
Now you try.
Go nice and slow...
Don't drink the bathwater.
I won't.
Go up to your shoulders and count to ten.
Okay.
One...
One, two...
two, three...
three, four, shut the door...
five, six, pick up sticks, seven...
four, five, six...
Daikichi, you're counting slow!
Don't be in such a hurry to eat.
Okay.
Hey, Rin...
What?
Nevermind...
Your curry's delicious!
Do I have to do it as long as you?
Oh, no... That's okay...
Mm... You know...
I'm not your father...
I know.
But I'm not your big brother either, right?
Nobody thinks that!
I'm just giving a for instance!
The question is, what am I then?
Daikichi!
That's my name...
Listen, and this is only
if you aren't against it...
What I'm trying to say...
How can I put it...?
Uh... What do you...
Rin, what would you think...
about me becoming your real father?
Daikichi, you...
become my father?
So, say we did that, your name
would become Kawachi Rin...
Kawachi... Rin.
No.
No...?
Don't you think it'd be
better if you had a father?
My father is Grandpa.
My name is Kaga Rin and I like it.
It's the same name as Grandpa.
That's important.
I see...
Daikichi should just stay Daikichi.
Daikichi?
What's wrong?
Are you crying?
This is sweat!
It's still only March...
Oh, shut up!
Just open your mouth!
It was open, but you were crying!
I said I wasn't crying!
Move your head up a little more...
'Kay...
Y'know, this'll always be your home...
Yeah.
Congratulations on Graduating from Nursery School
We mustn't forget what we believe.
Because the morning will surely come.
We mustn't lose our dreams.
Because one day they will surely come true.
The first step... Step to tomorrow...
Starting today, everything will be new!
Build that courage up, nice and big...
And take that first step out!
I understand.
You're gonna get fat, you know...
That's fine. Either way,
I'm good for nothing.
Give me one.
Forget it.
A sunny early Sunday afternoon
Let's go somewhere today
It's the same road I'm used to traveling
But I can see it sparkling so bright
With the sun shining down its warmth
And you here by my side...
I'm already high, high, high
I feel like dashing out
Sing, la, la, la
My voice out to forever
I'm already high, high, high
Ride the dancing wind
Sing, la, la, la
My voice springs up
Only babies get held like that!
That's what Sayaka-chan said!
Hah?! That's not true!
There are times when even adults
want to be held in someone's arms.
Adults?! Why?!
I don't know myself.
Is it still okay to be held, even
after I become a first-grader?
Why, sure!
I'll hold you no matter how old you are...
W-What?!
I'm sorry.
I should've held you before.
Hah?
I'll hold you the next
time you cry, Daikichi.
What the...?
Don't worry!
Am I raising Rin or is she raising me?
Sometimes I wonder...